tandolin.co.za 2012-12-16

# Privacy Policy

* ## Introduction

tandolin.com/tandolin.co.za (“Tandolin”) values the privacy and security of the information that you share with us. This Privacy Statement applies to information collected through www.tandolin.com/www.tandolin.co.za (the “website”). This Privacy Statement also applies to other information Tandolin receives in the The Republic of South Africa. This Statement describes how Tandolin collects, uses, shares, protects, or otherwise processes your personal information. **By using this website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Statement.**

* ## Collection and Use of Information

Tandolin collects minimal information to set up and manage accounts for our ecommerce services and to handle orders of goods and services from Tandolin.

You only need to provide Tandolin with your email address, Full name and username to enable purchasing through our merchant, [2Checkout.com](http://www.2checkout.com/), who may require personal information from you which they store securely on their servers such as:

  * names; phone numbers; mailing, billing, shipping, and email addresses;

  * bank account information; credit and debit card information; dates of birth; and identification documents.

Tandolin uses such information for:

  * website registration; enabling sales and other transactions; processing payments and settlement; sending payouts; handling orders; providing receipts;

  * providing customer service; providing dispute resolution, chargebacks, refunds, or related issues;

  * marketing and surveys; sending service update notices;

  * recovering debt and collections; detecting and preventing fraud; detecting and preventing violations of our legal agreements;

  * measuring, improving, and customizing our services; and

  * fulfilling other technical, logistical, financial, tax, legal, compliance, administrative, or back office functions.

Tandolin may also collect background information and credit checks from third parties to verify your identity; deter, detect, and prevent fraud and illegal activity; make business decisions; and as a part of our legal obligations. Tandolin retains such information for as long as reasonably required for business purposes or as reasonably required to comply with our legal obligations.

## Community Information

Tandolin collects information from you to post entries to our community website or forums. Such information may include your email address, Internet Protocol address, user name, date and time of signup, and date and time of posts to the forum.

Tandolin uses this information for the secure and efficient functioning of our website, to provide you with access to our community site, to detect and prevent violations of our legal agreements, and as part of any legal obligations related to our community website.

## Transaction Information

Tandolin collects information on each transaction conducted through our website. Such information may include the amount of the transaction; the goods purchased; the identity of the supplier, affiliate, and customer; payment type; currency; location; Internet Protocol address; and websites visited.

Tandolin uses such information for refunds, for customer service, for website optimization, or for other administrative or business purposes. Tandolin may share information related to the transactions you conduct through our website with suppliers, affiliates, or customers for the purposes disclosed in this Privacy Statement. Tandolin retains transaction information for as long as reasonably required for business purposes or as reasonably required to comply with our legal obligations.

## Customer Service Correspondence

Tandolin also collects information involving customer service correspondence. This information may include emails, internet chats, faxes, or telephone calls directed to our customer service centers. Tandolin processes this information to provide customer service, handle complaints or disputes, measure and improve our customer service, detect and prevent fraud, and detect and prevent violations of our legal agreements. Tandolin retains customer service information for as long as reasonably required for business purposes or as reasonably required to comply with our legal obligations.

## Cookies, Web Beacons, and Logs

Tandolin collects information related to your use of our website using cookies, web beacons, and log information.

Cookies are small files containing strings of text stored on your computer. Tandolin uses cookies to authenticate you as a user when you log in, track your session, deliver content specific to your preferences and interests, store the contents of your shopping cart, provide features related to payment and customer service, and provide other functions.

Web beacons are objects embedded into web pages that allow us to determine whether and for how long users view web pages. We use web beacons for site traffic reporting, unique visitor counts, auditing and reporting, personalization, and other functions.

Log information may include web requests, Internet Protocol address, operating system, browser type, browser language, date and time of your request, and cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. Tandolin uses this information to enhance the functionality of the website and to make your access more convenient, secure, and efficient.

Tandolin also uses information gathered from logs, cookies, and web beacons to monitor website performance; improve website design, functionality, and security; and assemble web analytics and activity trends. Tandolin retains such information for as long as reasonably required for business purposes or as reasonably required to comply with our legal obligations.

You may stop your browser from accepting cookies or web beacons. The Help portion of your browser should explain how to configure your browser’s cookie handling. Your browser may have add-ons that may help you block web beacons. You may have limited functionality if you block cookies or web beacons set by our website.

## Google Analytics

Tandolin uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service. Google Analytics uses cookies, web beacons, and other means to help Tandolin analyze how users use the site. You may find Google’s Privacy Policy at <http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacypolicy.html>.

* ## Choice

We will seek your consent prior to using your personal information in a manner incompatible with the purposes we described in our Privacy Statement at the time of collection. You may choose not to provide any personal information to Tandolin, in which case we will be unable to provide services to you.

* ## Sharing of Information

Tandolin only shares information as described in this Privacy Statement. Tandolin shares information with the following categories of third parties. Such third parties are prohibited by law or by contract from processing personal information for purposes other than those disclosed in this Privacy Statement.

## Organizations that Provide Services to Us

Tandolin discloses personal information to other organizations that perform services on our behalf. We require such organizations to use such information solely for the purposes of providing services to us and to protect the personal information with appropriate safeguards.

Such organizations include financial institutions; payment processors; money transfer service providers; acquirers; auditors; background and credit check organizations; fraud prevention service providers and anti-fraud networks; marketing service providers; database managers; customer service providers and representatives; debt collectors; and others who perform technical, logistical, financial, tax, legal, compliance, or administrative functions on our behalf.

These organizations may perform functions such as processing credit and debit card payments, sending wire transfers, providing background and credit checks, providing fraud checks, providing customer service, analyzing data, supplying marketing assistance, fulfilling orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and email, debt collections, and providing other financial, technical, logistical, tax, legal, compliance, or administrative functions.

Financial institutions, payment processors, and acquirers may share the information that Tandolin provides to them with other financial institutions or card networks in order to provide financial services, payment services, and to process payments. Fraud prevention service providers and anti-fraud networks may share the information Tandolin discloses to them with other fraud prevention service providers and anti-fraud network participants in order to provide fraud checks.

## Suppliers

Tandolin discloses personal information to its suppliers. Tandolin makes goods and services from suppliers available to customers for purchase. We have confidentiality agreements with these suppliers. We share personal information with suppliers to complete transactions, resolve customer comments or complaints, and for administrative and analytical purposes like accounting, billing and audits, information system management, and other uses.

## Customers

Tandolin discloses personal information to its customers. Tandolin makes goods and services from suppliers available to customers for purchase. We may share personal information with customers to complete transactions, resolve customer comments or complaints, and for administrative purposes like accounting, billing and audits, and other uses.

## Business Sale or Merger

Tandolin may share personal information in the event of a sale or merger of all or any portion of its business units. Such information remains subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Statement, unless an individual consents otherwise.

## Other

Tandolin may disclose personal information where:

  * required by law or by an order or requirement of a court, administrative agency, or other government entity, or by court rules concerning the production of records;

  * Tandolin has reasonable grounds to believe that use or disclosure is necessary to protect the rights, privacy, property, or safety of our users or others;

  * Tandolin has reasonable grounds to believe that the information relates to the breach of an agreement or violation of the law that has been, is being, or is about to be committed;

  * it is necessary for fraud protection, risk reduction, or the establishment or collection of funds owed to us;

  * it is necessary to enforce or apply our legal agreements, to pursue remedies, or to limit damages to Tandolin;

  * the information is public;

  * you have provided consent or with your direction; or

  * other reasons allow it or other laws require it.

When we are required or permitted to disclose information, we will not disclose more information than is necessary to fulfill the disclosure purpose.

Tandolin may disclose aggregate or statistical information to our business partners, for public relations purposes, or other purposes.

* ## Access

At your request, we will provide you with reasonable access to your personal information, so that you can review what we have stored and, if you choose, request corrections to it. You may request access by writing to us at the address listed in the Contact Information section below. After you request access, we will provide the personal information that you request as soon as practically possible and generally no later than thirty days following the request. If you wish to correct your personal information, please send us a written explanation of the particular information that you believe should be corrected. Where information will not or cannot be accessed or amended, we will tell you the reasons.

Tandolin stores, collects, and otherwise processes information mainly in Johannesburg, South Africa and through 2Checkout in Columbus, Ohio, U.S.A and/or PayPal.

* ## Security

Tandolin combines technical and physical safeguards with employee policies and procedures to protect your information. We work to protect your personal information during transmission by keeping it at the merchant's website [2Checkout.com](http://www.2checkout.com/), who use Secure Sockets Layer software, which encrypts the information that you provide online when making your purchase. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to protect your information. We will also continue to assess new technology for protecting information and upgrade our information security systems when appropriate.

Further, we permit only authorized Tandolin employees and third parties to access any personal information. If an employee misuses personal information, we may take disciplinary action, up to and including termination of employment. If any third party individual or organization misuses personal information, we will take action, up to and including termination of any agreement between Tandolin and that individual or organization.

* ## Data Integrity

Tandolin processes personal information only for the purposes it was originally collected and in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Tandolin takes commercially reasonable steps to ensure that the personal data is relevant, reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete, and current for the purposes for which it is used. Tandolin retains information for as long as reasonably required for business purposes or as reasonably required to comply with our legal obligations.

* ## Children

Tandolin does not sell products for purchase by children, but we do sell children's products for purchase by adults. We do not knowingly collect, maintain, or use personal information from children under age 13. If you are under age 13, do not share personal information with us.

* ## Links to Other Websites

When you click on a link on this website that takes you to a website operated by another company, you will be subject to that company’s privacy practices.

* ## Controlling Unsolicited Email

We may send you information about our products and services. You may log into the Profile Center and update your Preferences to stop receiving this information. You may also opt out of Tandolin's marketing list or update your information by notifying us at [privacy@Tandolin.com](mailto:privacy@Tandolin.com) / [privacy@tandolin.co.za](mailto:privacy@tandolin.co.za) at any time.

* ## Amendments

Tandolin may amend this Privacy Statement on one or more occasions by posting a revised statement on this website or a similar website that replaces this website. Tandolin will amend this Privacy Statement in a manner consistent with the Safe Harbor Principles.

* ## Enforcement, Dispute Resolution, and Verification

Please contact us with any questions or concerns related to this Privacy Statement by using the address listed in the Contact Information section below. We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints or disputes regarding personal information in accordance with this Privacy Statement. For complaints that have not been satisfactorily addressed, you may use the [BBB EU Safe Harbor Program](http://www.bbb.org/us/european-union-dispute-resolution/) and [file a complaint on the web](https://odr.bbb.org/odrweb/public/getstarted.aspx) or file a complaint by contacting:

Council of Better Business Bureaus, Inc.  
BBB EU Safe Harbor  
4200 Wilson Boulevard, Suite 800  
Arlington, VA 22203  
Phone: 703-276-0100  
Email: [eusafeharbor@council.bbb.org](mailto:eusafeharbor@council.bbb.org)

Tandolin elected to use the self-assessment method for verifying its compliance with the U.S. Department of Commerce Safe Harbor Program.

* ## Contact Information

If you have questions or concerns related to this Privacy Statement, you may contact us by email at [privacy@tandolin.com](mailto:privacy@tandolin.com) / [privacy@tandolin.co.za](mailto:privacy@tandolin.co.za) or by writing to us at:

Attn: Privacy Officer  
Tandolin Consultants cc  
116 Aletta Street, Laezonia  
Tshwane, Gauteng, 0026  
RSA
